[
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_001", "name": "OpenAI", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "AI safety company founded in 2015, creators of GPT-4 and ChatGPT, headquartered in San Francisco", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_002", "name": "Sam Altman", "type": "PERSON", "description": "CEO of OpenAI, co-founder who leads the company and its mission toward AGI", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_003", "name": "Greg Brockman", "type": "PERSON", "description": "President and co-founder of OpenAI", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_004", "name": "Ilya Sutskever", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Co-founder and former Chief Scientist of OpenAI, left in 2024 to start Safe Superintelligence Inc.", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_005", "name": "Elon Musk", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Co-founded OpenAI in 2015 and later founded xAI; CEO of Tesla and SpaceX", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_006", "name": "San Francisco", "type": "LOCATION", "description": "City in California where OpenAI, Anthropic, and xAI are headquartered", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_007", "name": "GPT-4", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Large multimodal model by OpenAI released March 2023, accepts image and text inputs, showing human-level performance on benchmarks", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0001_008", "name": "ChatGPT", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Conversational AI by OpenAI released November 2022; fastest-growing consumer app reaching 100M users in two months", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0002_001", "name": "Microsoft", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "Global technology company that invested $10 billion in OpenAI and integrated AI into Azure, Bing, and Microsoft 365", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0002", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0002_002", "name": "Satya Nadella", "type": "PERSON", "description": "CEO of Microsoft who described the OpenAI partnership as transformative for productivity software", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0002", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0002_003", "name": "Azure OpenAI Service", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Microsoft's cloud service integrating OpenAI models into Azure for enterprise customers", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0002", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0002_004", "name": "Microsoft 365 Copilot", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "AI-powered productivity assistant integrated into Microsoft 365 using OpenAI technology", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0002", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0003_001", "name": "Anthropic", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "AI safety company founded in 2021, creators of Claude, backed by Google and Amazon with $7.3B raised", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0003", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0003_002", "name": "Dario Amodei", "type": "PERSON", "description": "CEO and co-founder of Anthropic, previously worked at OpenAI", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0003", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0003_003", "name": "Daniela Amodei", "type": "PERSON", "description": "President and co-founder of Anthropic", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0003", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0003_004", "name": "Claude 3", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Anthropic's AI assistant family released March 2024 including Haiku (fastest), Sonnet (balanced), and Opus (most capable)", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0003", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Claude 3 Opus", "Claude 3 Sonnet", "Claude 3 Haiku"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0003_005", "name": "Constitutional AI", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "Anthropic's training methodology to make Claude helpful, harmless, and honest", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0003", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0004_001", "name": "Amazon Web Services", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "Cloud computing division of Amazon that invested $4 billion in Anthropic in 2023", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0004", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["AWS"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0004_002", "name": "Amazon Bedrock", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "AWS managed AI service offering Anthropic's Claude models alongside other foundation models", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0004", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0005_001", "name": "Google DeepMind", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "AI research lab formed April 2023 from merger of Google Brain and DeepMind, headquartered in London", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0005_002", "name": "Demis Hassabis", "type": "PERSON", "description": "CEO and co-founder of Google DeepMind", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0005_003", "name": "Jeff Dean", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Former head of Google Brain, Chief Scientist at Google", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0005_004", "name": "AlphaFold", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Google DeepMind system that solves protein structure prediction with atomic accuracy", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["AlphaFold 2"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0005_005", "name": "Gemini", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Google DeepMind's multimodal AI model family released December 2023; Ultra variant outperformed GPT-4 on MMLU", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Gemini Ultra"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0005_006", "name": "London", "type": "LOCATION", "description": "City in England where Google DeepMind is headquartered", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0006_001", "name": "Meta AI Research", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "AI research division of Meta Platforms (formerly Facebook)", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0006", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Meta AI"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0006_002", "name": "Yann LeCun", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Chief AI Scientist at Meta, pioneer of convolutional neural networks", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0006", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0006_003", "name": "LLaMA", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Meta's open-source large language model family; LLaMA 2 (July 2023), Llama 3 (April 2024) rivaling GPT-4", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0006", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["LLaMA 2", "Llama 3"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0007_001", "name": "xAI", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "AI company founded by Elon Musk in March 2023, creators of Grok, raised $6B in May 2024 at $24B valuation", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0007", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0007_002", "name": "Grok", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "xAI's conversational AI; Grok-1 is a 314B parameter mixture-of-experts model trained on X/Twitter data", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0007", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Grok-1"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0008_001", "name": "Mistral AI", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "French AI company founded April 2023, creators of Mixtral, raised $415M Series A, backed by a16z and Lightspeed", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0008", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0008_002", "name": "Arthur Mensch", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Co-founder and CEO of Mistral AI, formerly at DeepMind", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0008", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0008_003", "name": "Mixtral 8x7B", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Mistral AI's sparse mixture-of-experts model (December 2023) outperforming LLaMA 2 70B on benchmarks", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0008", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_companies_0008_004", "name": "Paris", "type": "LOCATION", "description": "French capital city where Mistral AI is headquartered", "source_chunk_id": "ai_companies_0008", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0001_001", "name": "Transformer", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "Architecture from 2017 'Attention Is All You Need' paper by Google Brain; replaced RNNs with self-attention for faster parallel training", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Transformer architecture"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0001_002", "name": "Google Brain", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "Google's AI research team that developed the Transformer architecture, later merged with DeepMind", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0001", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0002_001", "name": "BERT", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "Bidirectional Encoder Representations from Transformers by Google; pre-trained with masked language modeling, used in Google Search since 2019", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0002", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0002_002", "name": "Jacob Devlin", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Lead researcher on BERT at Google AI Language", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0002", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0003_001", "name": "GPT-3", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "OpenAI's GPT-3 (175B parameters, 2020) demonstrated remarkable few-shot learning; GPT-2 was 1.5B params (2019)", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0003", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["GPT-2"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0003_002", "name": "Alec Radford", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Lead researcher on GPT papers at OpenAI", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0003", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0004_001", "name": "RAG", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "Retrieval-Augmented Generation from Facebook AI Research (2020) combining parametric LM memory with non-parametric document retrieval", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0004", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Retrieval-Augmented Generation"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0004_002", "name": "Facebook AI Research", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "Meta's AI research lab that developed RAG, FAISS, and LLaMA", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0004", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["FAIR"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0005_001", "name": "GraphRAG", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "Microsoft Research system that builds a knowledge graph from documents (entity extraction + community detection) then retrieves via graph traversal and vector search", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Knowledge Graph Augmented RAG"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0005_002", "name": "Microsoft Research", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "Research division of Microsoft that developed the GraphRAG system", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0005_003", "name": "Darren Edge", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Principal author of the GraphRAG paper at Microsoft Research", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0005", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0006_001", "name": "FAISS", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "Facebook AI Similarity Search library (2017) for efficient billion-scale dense vector search supporting HNSW, IVF, Flat indexes", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0006", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["Facebook AI Similarity Search"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0007_001", "name": "Leiden Algorithm", "type": "TECHNOLOGY", "description": "Community detection algorithm (2019, Traag et al.) guaranteeing well-connected communities; improves over Louvain; used in GraphRAG", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0007", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0008_001", "name": "LangChain", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Open-source LLM framework by Harrison Chase (Oct 2022) for building chains, RAG pipelines, and agents; 80K+ GitHub stars", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0008", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0008_002", "name": "Harrison Chase", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Creator of LangChain; raised $25M seed round from Benchmark in April 2023", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0008", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0009_001", "name": "LlamaIndex", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Data framework by Jerry Liu (Nov 2022) for connecting custom data sources to LLMs with hundreds of data connectors", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0009", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["GPT Index"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0009_002", "name": "Jerry Liu", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Creator of LlamaIndex; raised $8.5M seed round in 2023", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0009", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0010_001", "name": "Hugging Face", "type": "ORGANIZATION", "description": "ML tools company (founded 2016) hosting 500K+ open-source models; raised $235M Series D at $4.5B valuation", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0010", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0010_002", "name": "Transformers Library", "type": "PRODUCT", "description": "Hugging Face's Python library with 100K+ pre-trained NLP models; the most widely-used NLP library", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0010", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": ["HF Transformers"], "attributes": {}},
  {"id": "ent_ai_tech_0010_003", "name": "Clement Delangue", "type": "PERSON", "description": "Co-founder and CEO of Hugging Face", "source_chunk_id": "ai_tech_0010", "confidence": 0.99, "aliases": [], "attributes": {}}
]